<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<research_info>

  <!-- Publications -->
  
  <pub>
    <id>bw_spillovers</id>
    <title>Spillover effects of early-life medical interventions</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal, Marianne Simonsen, and Sanni Breining</coauthors>
    <journal>Review of Economics and Statistics</journal>
    <vol_issue>104(1)</vol_issue>
    <date>January 2022</date>
    <pages>1-16</pages>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      We investigate the effects of early-life medical treatments on the treated children and their families. We use a regression discontinuity design that exploits changes in medical treatments across the very low birth weight (VLBW) cutoff. Using administrative data from Denmark, we establish that VLBW children have better health and higher test scores. We find that these benefits spill over to other family members: mothers enjoy better mental health, and siblings have higher test scores. Maternal mental health improvements seem to be driven by better focal child health and sibling spillovers by improved interactions within the family and parental compensating behavior.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>BW_Spillovers.pdf</doc>
    <doi>10.1162/rest_a_00982</doi>
  </pub>

  <pub>
    <id>gyn_jhe</id>
    <title>Low-risk isn't no-risk: Perinatal treatments and the health of low-income newborns</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal and Reyn van Ewijk</coauthors>
    <journal>Journal of Health Economics</journal>
    <vol_issue>64</vol_issue>
    <date>March 2019</date>
    <pages>55-67</pages>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      We investigate the effects of perinatal medical treatments on low-income newborns who are classified as low-risk. A policy rule in The Netherlands states that low-risk deliveries before week 37 should be supervised by physicians and later deliveries only by midwives with no physician present. This creates large discontinuities in the probability of receiving medical interventions only physicians are allowed to perform. Using a regression discontinuity design, we find that babies born slightly before the week-37 cutoff are significantly less likely to die than babies born slightly later. Our data suggest that physician supervision of birth reduces the likelihood of adverse events such as fetal distress or emergency C-section. Our results indicate that low-income women benefit from receiving a higher level of medical care even if no explicit risk factors have been recognized, pointing to challenges in identifying all high-risk pregnancies. "Back-of-the-envelope" calculations suggest this additional care is highly cost-effective.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>GYN_Midwife.pdf</doc>
    <doi>10.1016/j.jhealeco.2019.01.006</doi>
  </pub>

  <pub>
    <id>pdef</id>
    <title>Quality of higher education and the labor market in developing countries: Evidence from an education reform in Senegal</title>
    <coauthors>Dorothée Boccanfuso and Alexandre Larouche</coauthors>
    <journal>World Development</journal>
    <vol_issue>74</vol_issue>
    <date>October 2015</date>
    <pages>412-424</pages>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      While many studies examine the effect of primary education quality on labor market outcomes
      in developing countries, little is known about the effects at higher levels. We exploit the
      quasi-experiment provided by a large-scale education reform launched in Senegal in 2000 to
      investigate how quality improvements at the university level affect employment. Our
      difference-in-difference estimates suggest that young high-skilled workers experienced a nine
      percentage-point employment gain relative to older workers. They are also more likely to have
      "better" jobs (in the service industry or government), suggesting a reduction in the mismatch
      between the quality of high-skill labor demanded and supplied.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>PDEF_Senegal.pdf</doc>
    <doi>10.1016/j.worlddev.2015.05.007</doi>
  </pub>

  <pub>
    <id>nl_homebirths</id>
    <title>Saving lives at birth: The impact of home births on infant outcomes</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal and Reyn van Ewijk</coauthors>
    <journal>American Economic Journal: Applied Economics</journal>
    <vol_issue>7(3)</vol_issue>
    <date>July 2015</date>
    <pages>28-50</pages>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      Many developed countries have recently experienced sharp increases in home birth rates. This paper investigates the impact of home births on the health of low-risk newborns using data from the Netherlands, the only developed country where home births are widespread. To account for endogeneity in location of birth, we exploit the exogenous variation in distance from a mother's residence to the closest hospital. We find that giving birth in a hospital leads to substantial reductions in newborn mortality. We provide suggestive evidence that proximity to medical technologies may be an important channel contributing to these health gains.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>NL_Homebirths.pdf</doc>
    <doi>10.1257/app.20120359</doi>
  </pub>

  <pub>
    <id>SSM_cross_country</id>
    <title>Legal recognition of same-sex couples and family formation</title>
    <coauthors></coauthors>
    <journal>Demography</journal>
    <vol_issue>52(1)</vol_issue>
    <date>February 2015</date>
    <pages>113-151</pages>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      It has long been debated how legalizing same-sex marriage would impact (different-sex) family
      formation. In this paper, I use data on OECD member countries for the period 1980-2009 to examine
      the effects of the legal recognition of same-sex couples (through marriage or an alternative
      institution) on different-sex marriage, divorce, and extramarital births. Estimates from
      difference-in-difference models indicate that the introduction of same-sex marriage or of
      alternative institutions has no negative effects on family formation. These findings are robust to
      a multitude of specification checks, including the construction of counterfactuals using the
      synthetic control method. In addition, the country-by-country case studies provide evidence of
      homogeneity of the estimated effects.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>SSM_Comparative_Analysis.pdf</doc>
    <doi>10.1007/s13524-014-0361-2</doi>
  </pub>

  <pub>
    <id>Marriage_Netherlands</id>
    <title>The effect of same-sex marriage laws on different-sex marriage: Evidence from the Netherlands</title>
    <coauthors></coauthors>
    <journal>Demography</journal>
    <vol_issue>51(1)</vol_issue>
    <date>February 2014</date>
    <pages>317-340</pages>
    <notes>Winner of the 2008 Award for the Best Comparative Article Presented at an APPAM Research Conference</notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      It has long been argued that the legalization of same-sex marriage would have a negative impact
      on marriage. In this article, I examine how different-sex marriage in the Netherlands was affected
      by the enactment of two laws: a 1998 law that provided all couples with an institution almost
      identical to marriage (a "registered partnership") and a 2001 law that legalized same-sex marriage
      for the first time in the world. I first construct a synthetic control for the Netherlands using
      OECD data for the period 1988-2005 and find that neither law had significant effects on either the
      overall or different-sex marriage rate. I next construct a unique individual-level data set
      covering the period 1995-2005 by combining the Dutch Labor Force Survey and official municipal
      records. The estimates from a discrete-time hazard model with unobserved heterogeneity for the
      first-marriage decision confirm the findings in the aggregate analysis. The effects of the two laws
      are heterogeneous, with presumably more-liberal individuals (as defined by their residence or
      ethnicity) marrying less after passage of both laws and potentially more-conservative individuals
      marrying more after passage of each law.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>Marriage_Netherlands.pdf</doc>
    <doi>10.1007/s13524-013-0248-7</doi>
  </pub>

  <pub>
    <id>rt</id>
    <title>Do medical treatments work for work? Evidence from breast cancer patients</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal, William N. Evans, and Mikkel H. Pedersen</coauthors>
    <journal></journal>
    <vol_issue></vol_issue>
    <pages></pages>
    <!--
    -->
    <date>March 2025</date>
    <notes><![CDATA[
      <span style="font-weight: bold;">
        Conditionally accepted at <em>American Economic Journal: Economic Policy</em>.
      </span>
      An earlier version circulated under the title "The economic consequences of breast cancer treatments"
    ]]>
    </notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      We investigate the effects of radiation therapy on the mortality and economic outcomes of breast cancer 
      patients. We implement a 2SLS strategy within a difference-in-differences framework exploiting variation 
      in treatment stemming from a medical guidelines change in Denmark. We reproduce the results from an RCT 
      showing the lifesaving benefits of radiotherapy. We then show radiation therapy also has economic returns: 
      ten years after diagnosis, treatment increases employment by 37% and earnings by 45%. Previous work has 
      documented a substantial employment drop after a breast cancer diagnosis.  Our results imply that radiation 
      therapy can reduce this effect by 70%.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>Radiotherapy.pdf</doc>
    <!-- <doi>10.1007/s13524-013-0248-7</doi> -->
  </pub>

  <!-- Working papers -->

  <wp>
    <id>ad_children</id>
    <title>Antidepressant Treatment in Childhood</title>
    <coauthors>Sonia Bhalotra and N. Meltem Daysal</coauthors>
    <date>July 2025</date>
    <notes><![CDATA[
      <span style="font-weight: bold;">
        Submitted.
      </span>
      An earlier version circulated under the title "Teen antidepressant use and academic achievement"
    ]]></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      Mental health disorders tend to emerge in childhood, with half starting by age 14. This makes early 
      intervention important, but treatment rates are low, and antidepressant treatment for children remains
      controversial since an FDA warning in 2004 that highlighted adverse effects. Linking individuals across
      Danish administrative registers, we provide some of the first evidence of impacts of antidepressant 
      treatment in childhood on objectively measured mental health indicators and economic outcomes over time, 
      and the first attempt to investigate under- vs over-treatment. Leveraging conditional random assignment 
      of patients to psychiatrists with different prescribing tendencies, we find that treatment during ages 
      8-15 improves test scores at age 16, particularly in Math, increases enrollment in post-compulsory 
      education at age 18, and that it leads to higher employment and earnings and lower welfare dependence at 
      ages 25-30. We demonstrate, on average, a reduction in suicide attempts, self-harm, and hospital visits 
      following AD initiation. The gains to treatment are, in general, larger for low SES children, but they 
      are less likely to be treated. Using a marginal treatment effects framework and Math scores as the focal 
      outcome, we show positive returns to treatment among the untreated. Policy simulations confirm that expanding
      treatment among low SES children (and boys) generates substantial net benefits, consistent with 
      under-treatment in these groups. Our findings underscore the potential of early mental health treatment 
      to improve longer term economic outcomes and reducing inequality.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>AD_children.pdf</doc>
  </wp>

  <wp>
    <id>ml_screening_bc</id>
    <title>An economic approach to machine learning in health policy</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal, Sendhil Mullainathan, Ziad Obermeyer, and Suproteem K. Sarkar</coauthors>
    <date>January 2024</date>
    <notes><![CDATA[
        Currently revising
    ]]></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      We consider the health effects of "precision" screening policies for cancer guided by algorithms. We 
      show that machine learning models that predict breast cancer from health claims data outperform models 
      based on just age and established risk factors. We estimate that screening women with high predicted risk 
      of invasive tumors would reduce the long-run incidence of later-stage tumors by 40%. Screening high-risk 
      women would also lead to half the rate of cancer overdiagnosis that screening low-risk women would. We 
      show that these results depend crucially on the machine learning model's prediction target. A model trained 
      to predict positive mammography results leads to policies with weaker health effects and higher rates of 
      overdiagnosis than a model trained to predict invasive tumors.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>Screening.pdf</doc>
  </wp>

  <wp>
    <id>employee_health_flu</id>
    <title>Employee health and firm performance</title>
    <coauthors>Daniel A. Rettl and Alexander Schandlbauer</coauthors>
    <date>January 2025</date>
    <notes><![CDATA[
      <span style="font-weight: bold;">
        Revisions requested by <em>Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis</em>.
      </span>
      An earlier version is available as IZA Discussion Paper No. 15147
    ]]>
    </notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      Using administrative data on the universe of private firms in Denmark, we find that even temporary
      and small health shocks to employee health like seasonal influenza can significantly reduce firm 
      profitability. The effects are driven by labor-intensive firms and decrease in firm size and 
      financial flexibility, suggesting that firms that are better able to shift resources can insulate 
      themselves better. Our results indicate that employees are shielded from these negative effects, 
      while owners (especially of small firms) see reduced dividends. Back-of-the-envelope calculations 
      propose that all but the largest firms may benefit from subsidizing vaccination programs for 
      their employees.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>Flu.pdf</doc>
  </wp>

  <wp>
    <id>rwanda_educ</id>
    <title>Language of instruction and educational outcomes: Evidence from an education policy in Rwanda</title>
    <coauthors>Dieudonné Tamfutu Munsi</coauthors>
    <date>October 2021</date>
    <!-- <notes>Currently revising</notes> -->
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      We investigate the effects on educational outcomes of a sudden change in the language of instruction 
      in Rwanda from one non-native language (French) to another (English). This change, enacted in 2008, 
      affected all levels of education without any language training for students or teachers. Using a 
      synthetic control approach, we find that the change in the language of instruction led to an 
      immediate and persistent decline in primary school enrollment and to a decline in secondary school 
      enrollment at the time when the first cohort fully affected by the policy would have started 
      secondary school. As a direct consequence of lower school enrollment, we also find a reduction in the
      expected number of years of schooling. We provide suggestive evidence that the decline in enrollment
      is due to higher drop-out rates, mostly among students who are old-for-grade.
    ]]></abstract>
    <url></url>
  </wp>

  <wp>
    <id>rwanda_fertility</id>
    <title>The effects of education policy on teen pregnancy</title>
    <coauthors>Dieudonné Tamfutu Munsi</coauthors>
    <date>October 2021</date>
    <!-- <notes>Currently revising</notes> -->
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      More education is generally associated with delayed marriage and fertility. We investigate the causal 
      link between a policy that plausibly reduced educational attainment in Rwanda and teen fertility. In
      2008, Rwanda suddenly changed the language of instruction at all levels of schooling from French to
      English, despite the fact that a very small fraction of the population was able to speak English. This
      led to a significant reduction in primary and secondary school enrollment. Using both a synthetic
      control approach with aggregate data and a difference-in-differences approach with individual-level
      data, we document an increase in teen fertility as a result of this policy. Although more imprecise,
      our results also suggest that the effects are larger in urban areas.
    ]]></abstract>
    <url></url>
  </wp>

  <wp>
    <id>rwanda_health</id>
    <title>Education policies and the intergenerational transmission of health: Evidence from Rwanda</title>
    <coauthors>Dieudonné Tamfutu Munsi</coauthors>
    <date>October 2021</date>
    <!-- <notes>Currently revising</notes> -->
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      While better health has been shown to lead to more education, both in the developed and in the
      developing world, the causal link from education to health is less clear. In this paper, we examine
      the role of an education policy that presumably reduced educational attainment on the health of
      young adults affected by the policy and on children born after the intervention. Using aggregate
      data and a synthetic control method, we find limited evidence of an effect on the health of adults
      and some evidence of effects on the health of children. Our analyses help better understand the
      determinants of the intergenerational transmission of poverty and inequality in the context of a
      developing country.
    ]]></abstract>
    <url></url>
  </wp>

  <!-- Work in progress -->

  <wip>
    <id>gps_akm</id>
    <title>GPs and inequality in health</title>
    <coauthors>Janet Currie and N. Meltem Daysal</coauthors>
    <date></date>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[]]></abstract>
  </wip>

  <wip>
    <id>ig_nature</id>
    <title>Nature and nurture in the intergenerational transmission of mental health</title>
    <coauthors>Sonia Bhalotra, N. Meltem Daysal, and Jakob Søgaard</coauthors>
    <date></date>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[]]></abstract>
  </wip>

  <wip>
    <id>mh_penalty</id>
    <title>The labor market consequences of perinatal depression</title>
    <coauthors>Sonia Bhalotra, N. Meltem Daysal, Priyama Majumdar, and Tom Zohar</coauthors>
    <date></date>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[]]></abstract>
  </wip>

  <wip>
    <id>disability_generosity</id>
    <title>Disability benefits and risky behavior</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal, Mikkel H. Pedersen, and Jonathan Zhang</coauthors>
    <date></date>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[]]></abstract>
  </wip>

  <wip>
    <id>mh_stocks</id>
    <title>Stock market fluctuations and mental health</title>
    <coauthors>Alexander Schandlbauer and Daniel Rettl</coauthors>
    <date></date>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[]]></abstract>
  </wip>

  <wip>
    <id>health_risk_aversion</id>
    <title>Health shocks and risk aversion</title>
    <coauthors>Alexander Schandlbauer and Daniel Rettl</coauthors>
    <date></date>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[]]></abstract>
  </wip>

  <!-- <wip>
    <id>lep</id>
    <title>The effects of language proficiency on the health and health behavior of immigrants</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal and Ana Ferrer</coauthors>
    <date></date>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
    ]]></abstract>
    <link></link>
  </wip> -->

  <!-- Other Publications -->

  <other_pub>
    <id>DJOF</id>
    <title>Medical treatments and social mobility</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal</coauthors>
    <journal>Samfundsøkonomen</journal>
    <vol_issue>2023:2</vol_issue>
    <date>March 2023</date>
    <pages>18-26</pages>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      Economists have long been interested in understanding the relationship between health and 
      socio-economic outcomes. Existing research consistently links poor health during early childhood to worse
      well-being in the long-run, including health, educational attainment, and labor market outcomes
      (Almond and Currie, 2011; Almond, Currie, and Duque, 2018; Currie et al., 2010). Growing evidence
      also indicates that child health shocks affect the socio-economic outcomes of other family members,
      such as parental labor supply (Gunnsteinsson and Steingrimsdottir, 2019; Breivik and Costa-Ramón,
      2022; Eriksen et al., 2021; Adhvaryu et al., 2022), parental health (Burton, Lethbridge, and Phipps,
      2008; Adhvaryu et al., 2022), and sibling academic achievement (Black et al., 2021). A natural
      question then is whether medical care aimed at improving childhood health may alleviate or eliminate
      these negative long-run consequences
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>DJOF.pdf</doc>
    <doi>https://www.djoef-forlag.dk/openaccess/samf/samfdocs/2023/2023_2/Samf_4_2_2023.pdf</doi>
  </other_pub>

  <other_pub>
    <id>BJOG</id>
    <title>Re: A recent study by economists on the impact of home births on infant outcomes confuses the debate on home birth</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal and Reyn van Ewijk</coauthors>
    <journal>BJOG: An International Journal of Obstetrics &amp; Gynaecology</journal>
    <vol_issue>123:10</vol_issue>
    <date>September 2016</date>
    <pages>1713-1714</pages>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      Our reply to the letter by de Jonge et al (2016) on how to interpret our findings related to
      the effect of a hospital birth on low-risk newborn mortality in the context of the home birth
      debate.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>BJOG_letter.pdf</doc>
    <doi>https://dx.doi.org/10.1111/1471-0528.14250</doi>
  </other_pub>

  <other_pub>
    <id>medisch</id>
    <title>Thuisbevalling riskanter in arm gezin</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal and Reyn van Ewijk</coauthors>
    <journal>Medisch Contact</journal>
    <vol_issue>13</vol_issue>
    <date>31 March 2016</date>
    <pages>16-18</pages>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      A summary of our findings on the effects of a hospital birth on low-risk newborn mortality. (In Dutch)
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>Medisch_Contact.pdf</doc>
    <doi>https://goo.gl/TV3WiR</doi>
  </other_pub>

  <other_pub>
    <id>Demo_comment</id>
    <title>Reply to comment on 'The effect of same-sex marriage laws on different-sex marriage: Evidence from the Netherlands'</title>
    <coauthors></coauthors>
    <journal>Demography</journal>
    <vol_issue>51:6</vol_issue>
    <date>December 2014</date>
    <pages>2349-2350</pages>
    <notes></notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      My reply to Dinno (2014), who argues that finding no evidence of change in the marriage rate
      is not proof of absence of change and suggests using equivalence tests to verify that the
      same-sex marriage law had no effect on the different-sex marriage rate.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>Demography_Reply.pdf</doc>
    <doi>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13524-014-0348-z</doi>
  </other_pub>

  <other_pub>
    <id>Kenya</id>
    <title>Banking sector stability, efficiency, and outreach in Kenya</title>
    <coauthors>Thorsten Beck, Robert Cull, Michael J. Fuchs, Jared Getenga, Peter K. Gatere, and John Randa</coauthors>
    <journal>Kenya: Policies for Prosperity (edited by Christopher Adam, Paul Collier, and Njuguna Ndung'u)</journal>
    <vol_issue>Oxford University Press</vol_issue>
    <date>2011</date>
    <pages>2349-2350</pages>
    <notes>Also available as World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No. 5442, October 2010</notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      Although Kenya's financial system is by far the largest and most developed in East Africa and
      its stability has improved significantly over the past years, many challenges remain. This paper
      assesses the stability, efficiency, and outreach of Kenya's banking system, using aggregate,
      bank-level, and survey data. Banks' asset quality and liquidity positions have improved, making the
      system more resistant to shocks, and interest rate spreads have declined, in part due to reduction
      in the overhead costs of foreign banks. Outreach remains limited, but has improved in recent years,
      driven by mobile payments services in the domestic remittance market. Fostering a level regulatory
      playing field for all deposit-taking institutions is a key remaining challenge. Specifically, an
      effective but not overly burdensome framework for regulation and supervision of microfinance
      institutions and cooperatives is a priority. Maintaining an openness to new, and non-bank,
      providers of financial services, which has enabled the success of mobile payments, could also
      further outreach.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc></doc>
    <doi>http://dx.doi.org/10.1596/1813-9450-5442</doi>
  </other_pub>

  <!-- Permanent working papers -->

  <rip>
    <id>NL_Heterogeneity</id>
    <title>Heterogeneous effects of medical interventions on the health of low-risk newborns</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal and Reyn van Ewijk</coauthors>
    <date>November 2016</date>
    <notes>An earlier version is available as IZA Discussion Paper No. 9810</notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      We investigate heterogeneity in the impact of early-life medical interventions on low-risk
      newborns' health. A policy rule in The Netherlands creates large discontinuities in medical
      treatments at gestational week 37. Using a regression discontinuity design, we find no health
      benefits from additional treatments for average newborns. However, there is substantial
      heterogeneity in returns to treatments, with significant health benefits for newborns in the
      lowest income quartile and no benefits in higher income quartiles. We provide suggestive evidence
      that potential difficulties in risk screening among low-income women cause this heterogeneity.
      "Back-of-the-envelope" calculations suggest that providing additional treatments to
      all low-risk births as per the current policy rule is barely efficient, but a targeted policy
      focusing on low-income areas would be highly cost-effective.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>NL_Heterogeneity.pdf</doc>
  </rip>

  <rip>
    <id>GYN_Midwife</id>
    <title>Returns to childbirth technologies: Evidence from preterm births</title>
    <coauthors>N. Meltem Daysal and Reyn van Ewijk</coauthors>
    <date>December 2013</date>
    <notes>An earlier version is available as IZA Discussion Paper No. 7834</notes>
    <abstract><![CDATA[
      We investigate the impact of obstetrician supervision, as opposed to midwife supervision, on
      the health of low-risk newborns. We exploit a unique policy rule in the Netherlands that creates
      a large discontinuity in the probability of a low-risk birth being attended by an obstetrician
      at gestational week 37. Using a fuzzy regression discontinuity design, we consistently find no
      health benefits from obstetrician supervision, despite increased neonatal intensive care unit
      admission rates among births supervised by obstetricians. These results indicate potential cost
      savings from shifting supervision of low-risk deliveries, which represent the vast majority of
      all births, from obstetricians to midwives.
    ]]></abstract>
    <doc>GYN_Midwife_old.pdf</doc>
  </rip>

</research_info>
